CHRISTOPHER DENO

Fairfax, VA 22031 • (818) 671-8222 • christopherdenq@gmail.com cdenq.github.io • github.com/cdenq • linkedin.com/in/christopherdenq

SUMMARY

Early data scientist with 1.33 years professional experience and 3 years academic experience in data analytics, machine learning, database engineering, and full-stack software development. Art market background confers prioritization of customer-sense and unique holistic problem-solving skills. Avid self-learner and serial project-builder who strives to constantly grow, empower others, and add value to the community.

EDUCATION

University of Pennsylvania | Philadelphia, PA

Bachelor of Arts, Philosophy and Art History

Aug 2015 - May 2021

• Honors: John C. Parker Fellowship, 2016 (\$500 for statistical research in game theory model)

Post-Baccalaureate in Data Science

Sep 2021 – Mar 2022

Course Topics: Machine Learning, Data Analytics, ETL, Server Deployment, Fullstack Software Development

Stanford University | Stanford, CA

Non-Degree Opinion

Sep 2022 – Dec 2022

• Course Topics: Machine Learning Alignment

Foothill College | Los Altos Hills, CA

Associates of Science, Mathematics and Computer Science

Apr 2022 - Dec 2022

• Honors: Campus Business Innovation Challenge, 2022 (\$500 for risk prediction ML prototype)

Course Topics: Linear Algebra, Statistics, Probability, Diff. Eqns., Discrete Math., Cloud Computing, Multivariate Calculus

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

2U – Trilogy Education Services | *Assistant Instructor & Tutor* | Remote

(6 months) May 2022 - Nov 2022

- Helps manage Engineering & Data Analytics curriculums with instructor team; teaching and tutoring over 210+ hours to 35 students
- Successfully performs code reviews, provides feedback on projects, and teaches CS concepts

PNC Financial Services Group | Data Analyst Intern | Brecksville, OH

(3 months) Jun 2022 - Aug 2022

- Takes initiative in scaling and automation by introducing Python and ML/AI solutions to enhance standard data process
- Successfully created 8 data products used by 10+ managers, 80+ team members to monitor team performance, health, risk, and capacity

California State University: Northridge | ML Research Intern | Northridge, CA

(7 months) Nov 2021 - May 2022

- Researched graduate-level ML material, edited/created 280+ class slides, 10+ Java-to-Python code conversion samples
- Succeeded in collaborating, designing, and coding for graduate-level ML course curriculum with Professor Wen-chin Hsu

Wyzant.com | Freelance Computer Science Tutor | Remote

(9 months) Sep 2021 - May 2022

- Tutored 25+ students from high school to adult learners for 65+ hours; topics range from AP Computer Science to Intro. ML
- Succeeded in adapting teaching style, clearly communicating abstract computer science concepts, and mentoring students

Christie's Auctions & Private Sales | Gallery Intern | New York, NY

(3 months) Jun 2020 – Aug 2020

- Contributed to 6+ reports, appraisals, and collection package documentation; attended 3+ onsite auctions, hilling meetings
- Succeeded in helping Christie's adjust to accelerated digital marketplace and understand its market role amidst pandemic

Oasis Commissary (Non-Profit) | Founder | Philadelphia, PA

(3 years, 6 months) Sep 2016 – Mar 2020

- Started non-profit to address local community issue in dorm; wrote grant proposal to Dean, obtained vendor license from Philadelphia city
- Start-up succeeded and absorbed by Penn University; managed 21 staff, 2 managers, \$2000 bi-monthly budget, 6 marketing campaigns
- Succeeded in initiating own business development education, serving college dorm 3 years: \$1300 gross, 22k purchases, 180 unique clients

SELECTED PROJECTS

Full-Stack Machine Learning Web-App: Mushroom Edibility Predictor

Mar 2022

Python (SKLearn, Flask, Matplotlib), HTML/CSS/JS

github.com/cdenq/mushroom-edibility-predictor-web-app

- Full-stack web app that utilized mushroom data to predict edibility of mushrooms with user inputted features
- Trained 7 ML models on 60k+ data points to predict its edibility to within 80-99% accuracy, created 8 EDA graphs

Full-Stack Interactive Web Dashboard: Market Metrics on Video Game Industry

Jan 2022

Python~(BS4,~Flask,~Matplotlib),~MongoDB,~HTML/CSS/JS~(Plotly,~Leaflet)

github.com/cdenq/web-dashboard-of-video-game-industry

- Full-stack web app that scraped market metrics on the video game industry and dynamically visualizes based on user input
- Analyzed 10k data points, maintained 5 MongoDB collections, created 19 visualizations

SKILLS AND FRAMEWORKS

Languages: Python (OOP), Java, SQL (PostgreSQL), NoSQL (MongoDB), HTML/CSS/JS, APIs, Git

• Machine Learning: SKLearn, Keras, TensorFlow, PyTorch, Scipy, web-scraping

Cloud & DevOps: Google GCP, Google Collab, Hadoop/Spark, Docker, Github Pages, AWS, Microsoft Azure
Visualization Tools: Tableau, Google Sheets/Apps Script, Google Suite, Excel/VBA, Python (Matplotlib, Seaborn)

HOBBIES